<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Leadership is still about connecting with one another]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Leadership is still about connecting with one another]]></description>
        <link>http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 21:25:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 21:25:04 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What has inner and summit got to do with leadership?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What has <strong>inner</strong> and <strong>summit</strong> got to do with leadership?</h1>,<p>Innersummit has a story behind its name. Founded in 2004, it came about when I realised what happens at work and what happens in none work situations; the challenges we face can often feel like we are climbing mountains or climbing summits. That's when I realised, that everyone has the summits inside, the inner summits. At work I was working with twenty/thirty staff members needing to keep them inspired and motivated whilst the organisation was going through change; it often felt like climbing summits. Whenever I worked with people I often brought them back to the inner challenges, or the inner summits they had to face.</p>,<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FQPrp4v_EdPQ%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DQPrp4v_EdPQ&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FQPrp4v_EdPQ%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=b7d04c9b404c499eba89ee7072e1c4f7&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>,<p>Innersummit is all about those moments in business life that you have to dig a bit deeper in order to keep on moving forwards. It is the time when you need to continue believing that you can make it through a situation, which is over whelming. It is the leadership qualities expressed by thousands of people who have lead nations, businesses and communities.</p>,<p>In essence, Innersummit are the highest and lowest points in life that we internally face.</p>,<p>The Oxford dictionary defines summit as:</p>,<p><em>Pronunciation: /ˈsʌmɪt/noun </em></p>,<p><em>the highest point of a hill or mountain<br>the highest attainable level of achievement</em><br><br>Have you ever started a project, climbed a hill or even run a marathon? You will know that there comes a time when the battle in your mind begins to question whether you can keep on going. It is at these times that you find the stamina, resilience and courage to continue. And what a feeling when you complete that challenge. It is the ‘highest attainable level of achievement’ that you feel, why? Because you made it.</p>,<p>Similarly, have you ever approached, what seems to be an insurmountable mountain; leading a large team, businesses acquisitions, redundancy, starting up a new business. You will know that the ‘inner’ turmoil can often feel like that you are not going to make it. Yet Innersummit is about that very moment of decision to carry on, to get back up and to see it through.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/what-has-inner-and-summit-got-to-do-with-leadership/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d4823df0-f21a-4974-b63b-d18fa9fe73c5</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 19:12:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 Attributes of Toxic Leaders]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4 Attributes of Toxic Leaders</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6f51b184-6929-46d2-be3e-7793ffee7a10.png">,<p>Have you ever worked in an environment where it just feels toxic and you don’t feel you can actually work in that environment? What you might be observing in people around you, is toxic leadership, In this blog I’ll give you and overview of what the four attribute on what toxic leadership are.</p>,<p>Whenever you and I work, we can often observe and see in different people different attributes. Some are really good like influence and persuasion, but sometimes you might see toxicity, or what I call the four toxic attributes of leadership.</p>,<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FXIaaxzCI4PM%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DXIaaxzCI4PM&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FXIaaxzCI4PM%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=b7d04c9b404c499eba89ee7072e1c4f7&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>,<p><strong>Toxic Attribute – Manipulation</strong><br>I remember speaking with a friend who was preparing a report for a colleague who had to present at an executive board meeting. However, there was something about the request that he was being asked to do that made him feel that there was a hidden agenda. Sure enough, later on, it did transpire that there was something happening, the person who was presenting in the board took all the credit for the report! My friend felt like he was being manipulated. Have you ever seen that at work? That is the first attribute of toxic leadership, manipulation.</p>,<p><strong>Toxic Attribute – Domination</strong><br>When manipulation has faded away, you often see the second stage of toxicity. You go from manipulation to domination. This attribute has a pushy focus and presents in a way like; “your view no longer matters, It is about me, you can’t have a voice, and just do the work.”<br>Have you ever seen that at work ? Where someone is just too dominating, that is an attribute of toxicity, because it begins to squash the team, the environment, the culture of the company, and it drives out talent and reduces the likelihood remaining productive as a workforce.</p>,<p><strong>Toxic Attribute – Intimidation</strong><br>The third attribute of toxic leaders is intimidation. People who use this toxic attribute always have a caveat and a consequence attached to their leadership. Often controlled by fear, the language is ‘if you do that, I’ll make sure you will get this….’. This type of behaviour is possibly one of the most erosive attributes you can see within a team. Your team begin to operate is an atmosphere or a culture of “lets cover our back with emails” Have you ever seen that happen? Or you get behaviours where people come in and they are ‘walking on egg shells’. Grievances go up, sickness goes up, and it’s all because there is toxicity of intimidation within the culture of the company or the team.</p>,<p><strong>Toxic Attribute – Isolation</strong><br>The final attribute of toxic leaders is isolation. This is when the individual withdraws themselves from you, from the team and even from the company. In essence they use silence to control you. They withdraw you from meetings that you should have been attending, or they just don’t invite you. This is a very subtle but so powerful toxic attribute that erodes the confidence and the productivity of any person or any team in an organisation.</p>,<p><strong>The Antidote to Toxic Attributes</strong></p>,<ul><li>The antidote to manipulation is to confront reality. It is okay and fine to actually sit with someone who is being manipulating and confront the reality.</li><li>What’s the antidote to the next toxic behaviour? Domination. With domination, one of the key things that you need to do, is remain assertive. You need to dig deep and have the courage to voice your view, your contribution, and being assertive is the key antidote to domination.</li><li>What about intimidation? Having heard different people how they have dealt with behaviours of intimidation, there seems to be, one behaviour above all that helps. That is talk straight. There is no time when you or I should feel like that we need put up with people who are intimidating. The greatest thing you can do which will raise the respect and credibility of who you are, is to confront the intimidation and talk straight.</li><li>The antidote to isolation, is to create a transparent culture. You see, when someone withdraws from you, your antidote is to remain transparent. Remaining open is always key to combating isolating attributes. When the isolation finally subsides, you have always been seen and shown a transparency remaining accountable, openly and honest.</li></ul>]]></description>
            <link>http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/4-attributes-of-toxic-leaders/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">82f34da6-c65d-48ce-a08b-e4bf2cad5faa</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 21:22:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>