<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Leadership is still about connecting with one another]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Leadership is still about connecting with one another]]></description>
        <link>http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 13:54:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 13:54:11 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What has inner and summit got to do with leadership?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>What has <strong>inner</strong> and <strong>summit</strong> got to do with leadership?</h1>,<p>Innersummit has a story behind its name. Founded in 2004, it came about when I realised what happens at work and what happens in none work situations; the challenges we face can often feel like we are climbing mountains or climbing summits. That's when I realised, that everyone has the summits inside, the inner summits. At work I was working with twenty/thirty staff members needing to keep them inspired and motivated whilst the organisation was going through change; it often felt like climbing summits. Whenever I worked with people I often brought them back to the inner challenges, or the inner summits they had to face.</p>,<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FQPrp4v_EdPQ%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DQPrp4v_EdPQ&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FQPrp4v_EdPQ%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=b7d04c9b404c499eba89ee7072e1c4f7&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>,<p>Innersummit is all about those moments in business life that you have to dig a bit deeper in order to keep on moving forwards. It is the time when you need to continue believing that you can make it through a situation, which is over whelming. It is the leadership qualities expressed by thousands of people who have lead nations, businesses and communities.</p>,<p>In essence, Innersummit are the highest and lowest points in life that we internally face.</p>,<p>The Oxford dictionary defines summit as:</p>,<p><em>Pronunciation: /ˈsʌmɪt/noun </em></p>,<p><em>the highest point of a hill or mountain<br>the highest attainable level of achievement</em><br><br>Have you ever started a project, climbed a hill or even run a marathon? You will know that there comes a time when the battle in your mind begins to question whether you can keep on going. It is at these times that you find the stamina, resilience and courage to continue. And what a feeling when you complete that challenge. It is the ‘highest attainable level of achievement’ that you feel, why? Because you made it.</p>,<p>Similarly, have you ever approached, what seems to be an insurmountable mountain; leading a large team, businesses acquisitions, redundancy, starting up a new business. You will know that the ‘inner’ turmoil can often feel like that you are not going to make it. Yet Innersummit is about that very moment of decision to carry on, to get back up and to see it through.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/what-has-inner-and-summit-got-to-do-with-leadership/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d4823df0-f21a-4974-b63b-d18fa9fe73c5</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 19:12:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Emotional Intelligence]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FD56HpQBHAMs%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DD56HpQBHAMs&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FD56HpQBHAMs%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=b7d04c9b404c499eba89ee7072e1c4f7&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://youtu.be/D56HpQBHAMs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">84cb3cf2-0712-498d-8242-80a201133755</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 13:51:47 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[5:1 Rule. Changing Organisational Culture One Word at a Time]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2Fq2yDrZ09xng%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3Dq2yDrZ09xng&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2Fq2yDrZ09xng%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=b7d04c9b404c499eba89ee7072e1c4f7&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://youtu.be/q2yDrZ09xng</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3d2ec913-d893-4e80-bd7d-6857b90fa93d</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 13:53:18 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 Attributes of Toxic Leaders]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>4 Attributes of Toxic Leaders</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6f51b184-6929-46d2-be3e-7793ffee7a10.png">,<p>Have you ever worked in an environment where it just feels toxic and you don’t feel you can actually work in that environment? What you might be observing in people around you, is toxic leadership, In this blog I’ll give you and overview of what the four attribute on what toxic leadership are.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://chrisandreou.innersummit.co.uk/4-attributes-of-toxic-leaders/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">82f34da6-c65d-48ce-a08b-e4bf2cad5faa</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 21:22:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>